Guide to the Edna Clark Ericksen oral history audio recordings 1972-1982
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Edna Clark Ericksen oral history audio recordings
1972-1982
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 (801) 581-8864
A0339
Ericksen, Edna Clark, 1889-1983
45 audiocassettes
The Edna Clark Ericksen oral history audio recordings (1972-1982) consist of extensive interviews with Ericksen about her life experiences. Ericksen served in the Utah State Legislature in the 1930s-1940s and on the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints (LDS) Primary General Board.
Biographical Note
Edna Clark Ericksen was born in Auburn, Wyoming, on 19 November 1889 to Hyrum Don Carlos Clark and Ann Eliza Porter Clark. In 1905, at the age of sixteen, Edna left Star Valley and went to Paris, Idaho, in order to attend Fielding Academy, a LDS Church-sponsored combination elementary and high school. Although she did not complete her studies there, she enrolled at Brigham Young College in 1907. There she met her future husband, Ephraim E. Ericksen, who became the University of Utah's first Professor of Philosophy. They married on 8 June 1910. In 1920, Edna was called to the General Board of the LDS Primary organization, and was assigned the task of developing a program for boys between the ages of nine and eleven. Characteristically, Edna began by listening to the boys themselves, and then went on to develop what has been called the most successful program in the history of the Primary. It was at this time that Edna turned her imagination and flair for craftwork into a home industry that would contribute to the Ericksen family coffers for the next thirty years. She designed, made, and sold uniforms, badges, and insignias for the Primary and other local organizations. In 1932, Edna was elected to the Utah House of Representatives, where she served until 1935. Six years later, she was appointed to fill the State Senate seat vacated by Gordon Weggeland. She was elected in her own right the following year. After the death of E. E. Ericksen in 1967, Edna traveled to Europe, Mexico, and the Far East. In 1974, she was honored by the Utah Women's Political Caucus and the National Organization for Women for her contribution to women's causes.
Edna Clark Ericksen's family is committed to the preservation of her personal history. After a message was sent to the Clark Family Association by Clark S. Knowlton reminding the family that LDS Church authorities have instructed members to keep a record of their lives and the lives of their ancestors various family members taped interviews with Edna Clark Ericksen between 1972 and 1982. Edna Clark Ericksen died in Salt Lake City on 15 August 1983.
The Edna Clark Ericksen oral history audio recordings (1972-1982) consist of extensive interviews with Ericksen about her life experiences:
Tapes 1-3 were produced through the efforts of grandson Scott G. Kenney.
Tapes 4-19 are the result of conversations between Mrs. Ericksen and a grandniece and were intended to provide the basis for a life history.
Tapes 20-45 represent an attempt by Edna Clark Ericksen and Clark Knowlton to preserve a chronological record of her life.
The materials are arranged chronologially by interview date.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
See also the Edna Clark Ericksen papers (Ms 617) and photograph collection (P0425).
Ericksen, Ephraim Edward; Clark family; Ericksen family; Utah--Legislature; Democratic Party (Utah); Women in politics--Utah--History--Sources; Women legislators--Utah--History--Sources; Women in church work--Mormon Church--History--Sources; Mormon women; Polygamy--Personal narratives; Political Campaigns; Sound Recordings; Oral Histories; Sound recordings
- Edna Clark Ericksen and Heber D. Clark on polygamy, 1973 March 30; Audiocassette (Cassette 1-2)
- Primary board, Clark family, polygamy, 1973 August; Audiocassette (Cassette 3)
- Courtship, marriage and early married life, 1972 August; Audiocassette (Cassette 4)
- Christmas greetings to Edna, Chopin recital by J. M. Robinault, 1975 December; Audiocassette (Cassette 5)
- Childhood in Star Valley, polygamy, 1976 February 21; Audiocassette (Cassette 6)
- Edna's birth and childhood in Star Valley, polygamy, 1976 February 21; Audiocassette (Cassette 7)
- Childhood in Star Valley, 1976 March 13; Audiocassette (Cassette 8)
- Clark family life, polygamy, 1976 March 27; Audiocassette (Cassette 9-10)
- Courtship, 1976 April 17; Audiocassette (Cassette 11)
- Early married Life, 1976 May 22; Audiocassette (Cassette 12)
- Life in Beaver, Utah, life at 252 University Street, 1976 June 05; Audiocassette (Cassette 13)
- Ericksen family life, 1976 June 19; 1976 June 29; Audiocassette (Cassette 14)
- Death of Eliza Porter Clark, Ericksen family life, 1976 October 02; Audiocassette (Cassette 15)
- Childhood in Star Valley, Church callings, trail builders, 1977 January 16; Audiocassette (Cassette 16)
- Trail builders, Clark family reunions, Primary Board, 1977 January 29; Audiocassette (Cassette 17)
- Death of Howard Bendt Erickson, life at 252 University Street, 12 February 1977; Audiocassette (Cassette 18)
- Raising children, Family Life Conference, Utah politics, election to the Utah Senate, 1977 February 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 19)
- Childhood in Star Valley, early years and education, 1980 October 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 20)
- University of Chicago, childhood in Star Valley, polygamy, 1980 October 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 21)
- Childhood in Star Valley, polygamy, 1980 October 19; Audiocassette (Cassette 22)
- Clark family, childhood, life at 252 University Street, 1980 October 190; Audiocassette (Cassette 23)
- University of Chicago, LDS Church activity, trail builders, Church authorities, 1980 October 25; Audiocassette (Cassette 24)
- Utah House of Representatives, Utah Senate, 1980 October 25; Audiocassette (Cassette 25)
- Life in Star Valley, travels of the Ericksen family, trail builders, 1980 October 26; Audiocassette (Cassette 26)
- Trail builders, E.E. Ericksen's book published, 1980 October 26; 1980 November 01; Audiocassette (Cassette 27)
- Last years and death of E.E. Ericksen, Utah politics, Brigham Young statue commission, 1980 November 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 28)
- Williamsburg, Pennsylvania, childhood memories, crafts, foster grandparents, better homes campaign, 1980 November 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 29)
- Childhood in Star Valley, polygamy, Clark family, Edna's Education, 1980 November 23; Audiocassette (Cassette 30)
- Childhood in Star Valley, World War II, 1980 December 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 31)
- E.E. Ericksen, university life, trail builders, Native Americans, 1980 December 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 32)
- Edna's parents, early married life, Utah Legislature, 1981 January 17; Audiocassette (Cassette 33)
- Clark family, polygamy, 1981 February 01; Audiocassette (Cassette 34)
- Clark family, pioneering in Star Valley, 1981 February 07; Audiocassette (Cassette 35)
- Clark family, Ericksen family life, 1981 February 21; Audiocassette (Cassette 36)
- Women in public life, polygamy, Utah politics, Brigham Young statue commission, 1981 March 28; Audiocassette (Cassette 37)
- Clark family, polygamy, 1981 July 24; Audiocassette (Cassette 38)
  Side A
- Ericksen family life, LDS Church authorities, E.E. Ericksen at the University of Utah, Ericksen children as adults, 1982 July 02; Audiocassette (Cassette 39)
- Ericksen childrenm, Clark family, 1982 July 07; 1982 August 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 40)
- LDS Church reaction to "The Psychological and Ethical Aspects of Mormon Group Life," Ericksen family, 1982 August 18; Audiocassette (Cassette 41)
- University of Utah, LDS Church, 1982 September 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 42)
- Ericksen family life, 1982 September 08; Audiocassette (Cassette 43)
- Clark family, Knowlton family, polygamy, Ericksen family life, E.E. Ericksen's last years, Primary Board, 1982 September 08; 1982 September 22; Audiocassette (Cassette 44)
- E.E. Ericksen's last years, settlement of Star Valley, polygamy, 1982 September 22; Audiocassette (Cassette 45)